# Ruchitha Danepalli

Hvderabad.India

📕 +91 6302843388 | 💌 ruchithadanepalli19@gmail.com | 🖸 github.com/ruchidanepalli | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/rdanepalli

# **Profile Summary**

Enthusiastic real time Full Stack Java Developer with 1+ years of experience in java, spring boot, maven projects. Seeking opportunities where I can show my talent and enhance my skills to meet company goals and objective with full integrity and zest.

#### Education

### **Vardhaman College of Engineering**

June 2019 - May 2022

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering; CGPA: 8.59 / 10.0

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Coursework: Java, Python, Data Structures, Algorithms, Web Technologies, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Big Data, Routing and Switching Networks, Cyber Security, Information Security, Database Systems, Computer Networks

#### Kamala Nehru Polytechnic for Women

June 2016 - May 2019

Diploma in Computer Engineering; Percentage: 93.2%

Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Coursework: C, Java, Algorithms, Data Structures, Operating System, Computer Architecture, Relational Database Management System, Computer Networks, Web Technologies

# **Work Experience**

#### **Tata Consultancy Services**

June 2022 - Current

**Systems Engineer** 

Hyderabad, India

- · Proactively collabarating with different teams and professionals to develop minimum valuable products based on concept proofs utilizing user-centricdesign/agile methodologies.
- Built end-to-end software defined cloud interconnect solution for on-demand, real-time, reliable, and scalable multi-cloud connectivity.
- Implemented a scalable microservice architecture for a tele communication network web application where it can support the global users, international customer orders and processes it with low latency and high performance.
- Developed and maintained test coverage for all the new features which reduces the number of customer complaints by 70%.
- Developed custom RESTful APIs, RabbitMQ Queue Calls and optimized database queries for better performance accuracy.
- Designed and implemented a continuous integration pipeline using Maven and Jenkins, improving the quality and consistency of software releases by 85%.

**Salesforce** January 2022 - June 2022

#### **Associate Success Agent Intern**

Hyderabad, India

- Successfully Completed the Salesforce Admin 201 Certification Learning Path.
- · Good Understanding on Configuration Setup, Permission Sets, Object Manager and Lightning App Builder and Workflow/Process Automation concepts.
- Familiar with Apex Integration and Salesforce Lightning App Builder.
- · Active Participation in organizational activities and meetings.
- · Honed effective time-management skills while managing multiple tasks and priorities concurrently.
- Maintained a positive and professional attitude in the face of challenging tasks and tight deadlines.
- Provided weekly updates and reporting to Manager and Team Lead

• Familiar with cookie creation and data base connectivity using PHP.

• Built strong relationships throughout the organisation and have developed a comprehensive understanding of business processes and customer journeys.

#### **Creatick Solutions** November 2018 - May 2019

• Developed Web Pages and validated using JavaScript as per the company requirements.

• Familiar with Apache and WordPress Technologies

# Projects.

**Web Developer Intern** 

#### **Sentiment Analysis for Movie Reviews**

Hyderabad, India

Hyderabad, India

Vardhaman College of Engineering

June 2021 - October 2021

- This end-to-end project consists of a web application which uses NLP Techniques to analyse the given input text and classifies into the positive review and negative review. User will input a text to the model and get his results within seconds.
- I have used Stemming, Lemmatization, Tokenization, Stop Words for text processing and Multinomial Naive Bayes classification algorithm for classifications with discrete features.
- Performance is measured using confusion matrix classification and model is trained and acquired 94% accuracy.
- Technical Skills: Flask, HTML, JS, Google's TPU
- Libraries Used: nltk, pandas, numpy, sklearn, Seaborn, pickle.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

OCTOBER 31, 2023

#### **Pneumonia Detection Using Deep Learning**

Hyderabad, India

Vardhaman College of Engineering

November 2020 - April 2021

- This end-to-end project consists of a web application which uses Deep Learning algorithms to detect Pneumonia. User will upload a photo of chest x-ray and get his results within seconds. This is an easy to use application and can be deployed to production.
- · I have used Data augmentation, Image Processing, CNN and Transfer Learning techniques for image classification.
- Technical Skills: Keras, Flask, HTML, JS, Google's TPU, Overleaf, LaTeX.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

## Skills and Interests

**Programming and Frameworks** Python, Java, C/C++, JavaScript, SQL, Spring Boot, Mockito, JUnit, Bootstrap, Flask, React

**Databases** MySQL, MongoDB, Google Cloud BigQuery and Cloud Spanner

**Cloud platforms** Google Cloud Platform and Salesforce Platform

**Development tools and methodologies** Agile/Scrum, Maven, RabbitMQ, Postman, Git, Jenkins, JIRA, Docker, Kubernetes

LanguageFluent English, Telugu, and Conversational HindiInterestsMachine Learning, Robotics, and Cloud Computing

### **Certifications and Achievements**

2023 Google Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer

2022 Salesforce Certified Administrator

2022 CodeChef SRM's debugging contest bug crush 2.0 (solved 5 out of 5

2022 Python Programming by Cisco

2021 Introduction to Cyber Security by Cisco

OCTOBER 31, 2023 2